准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
上周  一集前所未见的海绵宝宝剧集
Last week a never-before-seen episode
尼克罗顿
of SpongeBob SquarePants
在尼克罗顿工作室桌底下被人发现了
was discovered under a desk at Nickelodeon Studios
现在全世界都在热切期待观看
Now all the world
is waiting in fevered anticipation to watch
海绵宝宝  失踪的剧集
the SpongeBob SquarePants "Lost Episode"
现在  即将播出失踪的剧集
Now, to present the lost episode
我们要来到加州恩斯诺
from Encino, California
有请海绵宝宝粉丝俱乐部的主席
the president of the SpongeBob SquarePants Fan Club
海盗派斯
Patchy the Pirate
派斯  派斯
Patchy, Patchy
孩子们来了
the kids are here
烫
Hot
波蒂  你就不知道
Potty, don't you know
派斯现在有私事吗
this is Patchy's private time?
大家好
Hello
你们来干嘛
What are you all doing here?
他们是来看失踪的剧集的
They're here to see the lost episode
可我没有失踪的剧集
But I haven't got the lost episode
因为我
because I
给弄丢了
well, I lost it
不要  派斯拜托
No, Patchy, please
别那么说  派斯
Don't say that, Patchy
可是真丢了
But it is
它失踪了  我不知道它哪去了
It's lost, and I have no idea where it is
你们还是把海绵宝宝给忘掉得了
so it's best if you forget all about old SpongeBob
怀念海绵宝宝
我居然会丢掉失踪的剧集
I don't believe I lost "The Lost Episode"
我从来没丢过任何东西
I never lose anything
那你腿呢
What about your leg?
丢了
Yeah
你一只眼睛呢
And your eye
眼睛丢了
And the eye
你一只手呢
And your hand
给我滚出去  你个臭鸟
Get out of here, you blasted bird
要是能有地图
If only I had a map
指引我找到失踪的剧集就好了
to tell me where the lost episode is
什么东西
What is it?
是张地图
It's a map
能带我找到我丢的海绵宝宝失踪剧集
It's a map to the lost episode of SpongeBob I lost
通向失踪剧集的地图
美梦要成真了
It's a dream come true
一定要去找到它  波蒂
We got to go find it, Potty
不过得先装上我的寻宝腿
First, I'll need me treasure-hunting leg
波蒂快来
Come on, Potty
时间不等人
Time's a-wastin'
在约翰逊太太家往前走十步
Ten paces past Mrs. Johnson's house
你们要不要吃饼干啊
Would you boys like some cookies?
先打包起来  约翰逊太太
Put them in a doggie bag, Mrs. Johnson
现在没空
Can't right now
我们要寻宝呢
We're on a treasure hunt
好  别着凉了
Okay, don't catch cold
唐恩市场
[ 英寻：海洋测量中的深度单位，约合1.829米 ]
在唐恩进口货品及熟食店往前五英寻
Walk five fathoms
past Don's Import Store & Delicatessen
唐恩进口货品及熟食店
分叉树
往分叉树走半里格
Half a league to the forked tree
[ 里格：长度单位，用于航海，约合3.18海里 ]
现在就只剩下
Now all that's left is
猴子湖之
七大试炼
猴子湖之七大试炼
The seven trials of Monkey Lagoon?
海神王保佑  都是为了海绵宝宝
Merciful Neptune, only for SpongeBob
都是为了海绵宝宝
Only for SpongeBob
成功了
We made it
成功挺过试炼了
We survived the trials
我马上就能挖到失踪的剧集了
I'm really going to dig this lost episode
挖到  懂吧
Dig it, get it?
懂 吧
你讲得好烂
You stink
臭
我刚洗过澡  才不臭呢
And I just got out of the shower
波蒂  我好像挖到什么了
Hey, Potty, I think I hit something
真是聪明
Clever--
把财宝埋在地面上
bury your treasure above the surface
找到了
This is it
我也不知道这什么意思
I don't know what it means either
不过该找的都找到了
but I got what I came for
波蒂快来  时间不等人
Come on, Potty, time's a-wastin'
好耶
Yeah
爆米花
Popcorn
汽水
soda
腌大蒜
pickled garlic
波蒂  赶紧按遥控器
Hurry, Potty, hit the remote
播放
一定会特好看
This is going to be great
海绵宝宝  失踪的剧集
真不敢相信
I can't believe it--
又有海绵宝宝看了
more SpongeBob
太激动了
This is so exciting
要来了
Here it comes
别吵
Pipe down
就这
That's it?
失踪的剧集就这吗
That's "The Lost Episode"?
就只是一堆便宜的循环走路动画
That was just a bunch of cheap walk cycles
太亏了
What a rip
海绵宝宝背叛了我们
SpongeBob betrayed us
我真后悔
I'm sorry
打一开始办了这家破粉丝俱乐部
I ever started this stupid fan club in the first place
我要把我的海绵宝宝周边全扔了
I'm going to get rid of all my SpongeBob stuff
全扔了
All of it
我要跑路
I'm going to run away
就这么办
That's what I'll do--
跑路
run away
海绵宝宝第118集
真正的失踪剧集
[ 实为第59集 ]
天啊  真是性急
Jeez, what a hothead
现在播出真正的失踪剧集
And now the real lost episode
派斯  回来
Patchy, come back--
还有呢
there's more
真的吗
Really?
万岁
Hooray
来看吧
Let's watch
会飞的
海绵宝宝
分镜总监
循环走路动画导演
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
水母田
这里有一位得意的水母捕手
Here we see the proud jellyfish hunter
他一动不动地站着
He stands motionless
诱骗水母  让它们误以为自己很安全
to lure the jellyfish into a false sense of security
待到猎物一靠近
and when his prey ventures too close
他便立刻行动
he springs into action
我向你致敬  宏伟的水母
I salute you, old majestic jellyfish
你对天空的驾驭能力无人能及
Your command of the sky is unmatched
飘浮在我的水母网所不能及之处
floating just out of the reach of my net
却又近在咫尺
but near enough
足以让我欣赏你桀骜不驯的美
that I can see your untamed beauty
但愿我能与你们共同飞上天去
If only I could join you there in the air
自在飘浮  无忧无虑
Floating free without a care
希望我能飞翔
I wish I could fly
俯瞰一切  转变我的目光
And see things with a different eye
我可以飞  扶摇万里
I would fly so very high
触摸天空
and touch the sky
而且不必过问为什么我不会飞
And never have to ask why it is that I can't fly
等一下
Wait a minute
差点忘了海绵爷爷给我的教诲了
I'm forgetting the words of Grandpa SquarePants
假如我们注定会飞
If we were meant to fly
那么头上就得有螺旋桨
we'd have propellers on our heads
背上就得有喷气引擎
or jet engines on our backs
我一定要遵从他的建议
I'm going to follow his advice, by gum
我要发明一个飞天机器
I'll invent a flying machine
那是什么装置  海绵宝宝
What's that contraption, SpongeBob?
派大星  那是飞天机器
That, Patrick, is a flying machine
笑什么笑
What's so funny?
这就像是我爷爷曾经常说的话
It's like my grandpa used to say
假如我们注定会飞
If we were meant to fly
我又不是你爷爷
I'm not your grandfather
那我要飞了  派大星
Well, here I go, Patrick
我要跟水母一起飞
I'm off to fly with the jellyfish
点火开关
Ignition
正常
Check
起落架
Landing gear
正常
Check
免费花生
Complimentary peanuts
正常得不得了
Checkaroo
准备起飞了
Ready for takeoff
你把简金斯农夫的粮仓切了个洞
You cut a hole in Farmer Jenkins' grain silo
别提醒我
Don't remind me
城里人跟他们的飞天机器果然没好事
I knew no good would come from
city folk and their flying machines
给我得了
That's it
我们
We
我们最好照他说的做
we better do what he says
他会种粮食
He knows how to grow food
虽然花了一整个晚上
Well, it took me all night
但我做好了
but here they are--
新蓝图
the new blueprints
跟上次那个可不一样了
I wasn't even close with that last one--
还螺旋桨  方向舵呢
propellers, rudders
这次绝对飞得起来
This one's going to fly
我有感觉
I can feel it
好了没  派大星
Ready, Patrick?
好了
Ready
成功了  派大星
It's working, Patrick
我飞起来了
I'm flying
我
I'm
掉下来了
falling
可以了  派大星
This is it, Patrick
物理学都研究明白了
The physics are all here
这次我一定飞得起来
This time, I'm going to fly
看好
Behold
天啊  要开生日派对了
Oh, boy, a birthday party
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
这是海绵飞天机三型
this is the SquarePants Flyer Mark III
只要挪开砖头
All you do is remove the brick--
或者说压舱物
or ballast--
就
and
还是另起炉灶吧
Well, back to the drawing board
现在能吃蛋糕了吗
Can we have the cake now?
祝你祝你生日快乐
Happy, happy birthday to you
准备好大开眼界吧
Patrick, get ready to say, "Eureka"
好
Okay
出发
Go
成功了
It's working
我飞起来了
I'm flying
快看那个绑着风筝的家伙
Look at that guy tied to a kite
他干嘛那样
Why is he doing that?
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness
不用怕  被束缚在地面的居民们
Do not be afraid, Earthbound people
我并不是只飞天怪物
I am not a flying monster
而是你们的一员
I am just one of you
派大星
Patrick
便宜货超市
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir
快件
我想归还这个风筝
but I'd like to return this kite
我认得你
I know you
对啊  今天的报纸上有报道
Yeah, from today's paper
裤头村新闻
本地疯子欲飞行
"Local nutcase tries to fly"
我追个梦就成疯子了吗
I'm a nutcase because I follow my dreams?
反正发明了电灯泡的那位也饱受嘲笑
Well, they laughed at the guy
who invented light bulbs, too
才没这回事
No, they didn't
等着瞧
You'll see
妈  你看
Look, Mom
是裤头村鸟人
it's the Birdman of Bikini Bottom
不知道他干嘛还用腿走路
I wonder why he's still using his legs
快啊  鸟人
Come on, Birdman
扇动翅膀飞起来啊
Flap your wings and fly
鸟人
Hey, Birdman
去看下你家鸟蛋吧
going to check on your eggs?
估计他还在找雕像拉屎呢
Maybe he's looking for a statue to poop on
你们就笑吧
Go on and laugh
今天的裤头村可真是可悲
but it is a sad day in Bikini Bottom
竟敢嘲笑一位怀抱远大梦想的人
when a guy is ridiculed for having dreams
你以为就你一个身怀未竟的梦想啊
You think you're the only one with unfulfilled dreams?
我本来应该是个开音乐会的钢琴家
I was supposed to be a concert pianist
结果后来我才发现我没手指
until I realized I didn't have any fingers
我们都有过梦想
We all had dreams
你凭什么觉得自己了不起
What makes you so special?
抓住他
Let's get him
滚越远越好
Good riddance
大梦想家
dreamer
清淤
至少不会变得更糟
Well, it can't get any worse
羽毛运送
看来我话讲早了
I guess I spoke too soon
海绵宝宝还能学会飞吗
Will SpongeBob learn to fly?
不要走开
Stay tuned
水母们又飞走了  小蜗
There they go again, Gary
看来没法跟水母一起畅游空中了
I suppose I'll never join them in the sky
只能困在地上
I'll be stuck on the ground
一辈子无法飞行
sentenced to a flightless life
好吧  看来一切梦想注定无法实现
Oh, well, I guess all dreams aren't meant to come true
回归现实吧
Back to reality
不对  小蜗
No, Gary
我的梦想很傻
my dreams are silly
开
喂
Hello
不对  我不是裤头村鸟人
No, this isn't the Birdman of Bikini Bottom
什么
What?
不对  我才没住鸟笼
No, I certainly do not live in a birdcage
你谁啊
Who is this?
倪娘
"Joe Mama"?
给我听好  姓倪的
Well, listen up, Joe
我就直说了  飞行根本不可能
I hate to break it to you, but flying is impossible
现在我得挂了
I have to go now
头刚撞天花板上了
My head just hit the ceiling
你看  小蜗
Look, Gary
我
I
我好像飞起来了
I think I'm flying
水母田  我来了
Jellyfish Fields, here I come
妈  快看
Mom, look
是那个飞人
It's the flying guy
原来他到头来不是个疯子
I guess he wasn't a lunatic after all
我在飞翔
I'm flying
他在飞翔  他在飞翔
He's flying, he's flying
他真的真的在飞翔
He's really, really flying
群众笑  过客嘲
They laughed, they scoffed
当时我无法飞云霄
before I had liftoff
但他正在飞翔  在空中飞得高
But now he's flying, he's flying high in the sky
虽然我很想留一句  我早说过
I'd love to hang around to say "I told you so"
但是前往水母田才适合我
But it's off to Jellyfish Fields I go
水母田
我可不愿意走大马路
Roads and streets are not for me
救命
Help
救命啊
Please help
我的蜗牛困上了树
My snail is up a tree
我从小就一直在养着它
I've had her since I was a little girl
但看样子它将命丧黄泉
But now it looks like the end of her world
不要
No
接到了
Gotcha
下次试试坐电梯
Next time, try the elevator
谢谢你  鸟人
Thank you, Birdman
从未感到这么自在
I have never felt so free
万里长空是我热衷的地带
High in the sky is the place for me
云端之上为朋友出手相助
Helping friends from up above
这是我的深深爱慕
These are the things that I love
我会帮蟹老板取回他的硬币
I'll help Mr. Krabs reclaim his dime
我发财了
I'm rich
拯救派大星  逃离这出哑剧
And I'll save Patrick from this mime
谢了  兄弟
Thanks, buddy
就连痞老板也需要帮助
Even Plankton needs some help
此时此刻他被海草缠住
When he gets tangled in the kelp
麻烦你放我下来
Please put me down
裤头村新闻
裤头村的大众正广泛热议
All of Bikini Bottom is abuzz over
一位神秘飞人帮手的真实身份
the identity of a mysterious flying man
who helps people
新闻
他找到了我的假发
He found my hairpiece
他会帮大家忙
He helps people
还会飞  还会帮大家忙
and he flies and he helps people
谁知道他还会用什么英勇之举
Who knows what superhero act of courage
震撼到我们呢
he'll astound us with next?
不好  酷乐湖灯塔的灯灭了
Oh, no, the light in the Goo Lagoon lighthouse went out
简金斯水手要开上海岸线了
and sailor Jenkins is headed for the coastline
不种田了我可真高兴
I'm glad I gave up farming
我来了
I'm coming
谢了  神秘的飞人
Thanks, mysterious flying man
城里人跟他们的飞天机器果然没好事
I knew no good would come from
city folk and their flying machines
一天的好事也做得差不多了
That's enough good deeds for one day
我跟水母们还有一场约会呢
I've got a date with a flock of jellyfish
海绵宝宝  小子
SpongeBob, son
我需要你跟你的神奇裤子
I need you and your magical pants
可是蟹老板  我发明这裤子
But, Mr. Krabs, I invented these pants
是要跟水母一起飞的
so I could fly with the jellyfish
要是我一直帮大家忙
If I keep doing favors for people
我的梦想就没办法成真了
I'll never get to make my dreams a reality
可是海绵宝宝  这次情况特别紧急
But, SpongeBob, it's an emergency
出发
Let's roll
要去哪  蟹老板
Where to, Mr. K?
我的船库
My garage
没问题
You got it
有什么紧急情况  蟹老板
What's the emergency, Mr. Krabs?
你确定准备好了吗  小子
You sure you're up for it, boy?
我的裤子多半能搞定
I think my pants can handle it
我需要你
I need you
什么事
Yes?
扫除
to clean
扫除犯罪吗
Clean up crime?
我的船库
my garage
你紧急情况就那个吗
That's your emergency?
可是海绵宝宝  众所周知
But, SpongeBob, everyone knows
飞起来就更方便扫船库了
it's easier to clean a garage when you can fly
好  蟹老板
All right, Mr. Krabs
我这就扫你的船库
I'll clean your garage
以后就别来找我帮忙了
But after this, no more favors
完成  蟹老板
All done, Mr. Krabs
可回收垃圾呢
And the recyclables?
真见鬼
Aw, shrimp
终于啊
Finally
水母田  我来了
Jellyfish Fields, here I come
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
派大星有麻烦了
Patrick's in trouble
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
怎么了  兄弟
What is it, buddy?
能帮我挠肚皮吗
Will you scratch my tummy?
能帮我挑领带吗
Help me pick out a tie?
能清理我浴缸吗
Clean my bathtub?
能结算我的账目吗
Balance my checkbook?
能帮忙散播邪恶话语吗
Help spread the word of evil?
邪恶
能解开我电话线吗
Untangle my phone cord?
能做我几何作业吗
Do my geometry?
能跟我植物对话吗
Talk to my plants?
能搓我头皮吗
Rub my scalp?
好耶
Oh, yeah
等一下
Wait a minute
我现在应该是在水母田里才对
I'm supposed to be at Jellyfish Fields right now
结果我却是在搓你头皮
but instead I'm rubbing your scalp
更何况我根本就不认识你
and I don't even know who you are
可我们是小学同学
But we went to elementary school together
丹尼斯吗
Dennis?
好耶
Oh, yeah
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
要是甩不掉那群占便宜的
If I don't give these feverish favor-seekers the slip
我就没法跟水母一起飞了
I'll never get to fly with the jellyfish
他在那
There he is
他要逃跑了
He's getting away
他还有忙没帮到我们呢
No, he owes us favors
抓住他
Get him
我就快到水母田了
I'm almost at Jellyfish Fields
我就快到了
I'm going to make it
他往水母田飞过去了
He's headed for Jellyfish Fields
这下抓不到他了
We'll never catch him now
我来搞定
I'll take care of this
炮弹简金斯
是炮弹简金斯
It's Cannonball Jenkins
我早说过
I told you
城里人跟他们的飞天机器准没好事
nothing good would come from
city folk and their flying machines
我们干了什么好事
What have we done?
大家快
Come on, everybody
应该要好好安葬他
I think a proper burial is in order
这种裤子一辈子只会出现一次
A pair of pants like these
come around once in a lifetime
美好时光不长久
Well, it was fun while it lasted
到头来我注定没办法飞
I guess I'm not meant to fly after all
我的水母朋友在帮我飞
My jellyfish friends are helping me fly
而且还不用裤子
Without pants
看来这一切的道理都是
I guess it just goes to show
飞行不需要飞机
You don't need a plane to fly
塑料翅膀会让你哭泣
Plastic wings may make you cry
风筝只有起风才能用
Kites are made for windy days
气球躺椅容易飞离
Lawn chair with balloons fly away
充气的裤子
Inflatable pants
从此可以告辞
You may as well skip
如果想要飞  需要的
If you want to fly, all you need
就是友谊
Is friendship
对
Yeah
再见  水母们
Good-bye, jellies
你们教会了我宝贵的一课
You taught me a valuable lesson
虽然不太确定这一课是什么
Although I'm not quite sure what it was
一起飞到匹萨店买片匹萨吃吧
Let's fly down to the pizza house for a slice
我不会再飞了  派大星
No more flying for me, Patrick
水母能自在飞行就够了
I'll leave that to the jellyfish
随你便
Suit yourself
难道派大星刚刚
Did Patrick just
才不会
Nah
是不是很好看啊  孩子们
Wasn't that great, kids?
再看一遍吧
Let's watch it again
你这提议不错  波蒂
That's a great idea, Potty
遥控器呢
Where's the remote?
我遥控器丢了
I lost the remote
这种东西就应该做得
They should make those things
我的遥控器
My remote
谢了  陌生人
Thanks, stranger
不客气  派斯
Don't mention it, Patchy
现在呢
Now
哪颗破按钮才是倒带按钮呢
which one of these cockamamie buttons is "Rewind"?
这颗不是
That's not it
又错了
Wrong again
我来按
Let me do it
起开
Get away
那是电灯开关
That's the light switch
给我拿来
Give me that
那是墨西哥街头乐队按钮
That's the "Mariachi Band" button
我恨高科技
I hate technology
倒带啊  破东西
Rewind, darn you
要完蛋了
Failure ahoy
不要  停
No, stop
停
stop
给我回去
Go back
破铜烂铁
infernal machine
完了  我把失踪的剧集毁了
Oh, no, I've ruined the lost episode
这下它永远消失了
Now it's lost forever
永远消失了
Lost forever
天啊  真是个废物
Oh, boy, what a loser
看来失踪的剧集会一直消失下去了
Well, I guess the lost episode will remain lost
但无论有没有带子
But tape or no tape
只要天上还有星星
as long as there are stars in the sky
海绵宝宝会永远活在我们的心中
SpongeBob will live on in our hearts and in our minds
快滚吧
Now get lost
我是说  再见
I mean, bye
不对  说真的
No, really
滚吧
get lost